William Pratt

925.785.1106 billp@billpratt.net 970 Harness Ct #18, San Ramon, CA 94583

Profile

I have spent over 20 years working in technology, specializing in Unix systems and software engineering. While I enjoy the daily challenges my profession provides, I am seeking an opportunity to grow by increasing the amount of time I spend on the business side of technology. I am ready to move into a manager or director level position where I can leverage my experience and engineering mindset to shape the technological direction of a company while remaining in touch with the systems and software. Not only can I speak the language of those I wish to lead, I can also provide direction and utilize resources to help all of us, myself included, learn and grow. I strive to work in an environment where I am immersed with those I respect including the employees on my team. Those that are in the trenches every day have a unique position to know the environment and tools intimately. I realize that every day and will lean on that while in this position. I sit in a unique position in my field as many say I have an amazing engineering mind coupled with the sales ability to work with the business and customers to deliver solutions that truly satisfy everyone involved. I can work closely with all sides, so well so that many forget which group I am technically working for. These unique talents, combined with my 20+ years of experience, align me exactly with the needs of this position. Given this opportunity to grow would be immensely rewarding to me. I really enjoy a challenge, it is truly what keeps me motivated and driven. You may view my Github at http:// github.com/williampratt. Unfortunately many repos are private and some under NDA. If you would like further samples I would be happy to provide them. Specialties: Leading Software Development Teams using a hands-on approach, Ruby / Ruby on Rails, Amazon Web Services, Hadoop, Perl, Web technologies (html, css, javascript, etc), C++, C#, Unix / Linux systems engineering, FortiGate, Juniper, Foundry, Redback, Mysql, Oracle, MSsql

Experience

OWNER / LEAD DEVELOPER AT HIVEMIND ENGINEERING; SAN RAMON, CA - 2012-PRESENT

Hivemind Engineering provides enterprise level development, monitoring and backups to small and medium businesses. While our specialty is E-Commerce, our services apply to a broad range of companies in this market. Please contact us today for more information. Packages and custom solutions start at surprisingly reasonable costs!

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER AT MALWAREBYTES: SAN JOSE, CA - APRIL 2015 - NOVEMBER 2015

I started at Malwarebytes as a RoR developer strictly. I spent countless hours increasing test coverage from 24 to 95+ percent. I eventually took over devops for my group and spent a lot of time in AWS. I also redesigned the event system to use fluent brokers. This not only separated concerns but it also solved a major issue; every time Influxdb would go down it would take the app with it. I also contributed a lot to the Influx- ruby gem as well as influx.

ENGINEERING LEAD AT ONELOGIN; SAN FRANCISCO, CA - JULY 2014 - FEBRUARY 2015

90% of my time was Ruby / RoR development on the main backend auth systems. I also began developing an OSX OpenDirectory setup that would allow multiple companies to simultaneously share a single directory (built in Linux) without colliding. I was successful in that project, however I left the company before it was ever integrated into the product. This was a difficult task requiring a lot of ingenuity as I could find no Internet postings where someone had successfully done so.

SENIOR RUBY SOFTWARE ENGINEER AT DEMANDBASE; SAN FRANCISCO, CA - JUNE 2012 - JUNE 2014

DevOps can be defined in at least 2 ways. The first is a complete separation of system operations from developers, yet with their input. The infrastructure is then automated based on their needs. The second, and surely not the last, is where developers manage the operations alongside their development tasks. The second, however, requires developers with extensive systems experience which is a rare thing. At Demandbase, we went with option 2 allowing developers to build their own environments (with mentoring from more senior systems engineers) alongside their applications. I enjoyed this as I knew my application well, what it needed, and when to tweak it if needed. We ran both continuous integration and continuous deployment. They app would auto-deploy on regular intervals. I spent 99% of my time here in Ruby, Rails, Sinatra, Grape, and Chef. The remaining time was the little bits I had to manage manually in AWS. I do have extensive Unix experience

and mentored many during this time. I was also willing to build entire environments for others when time constraints were tough. I did spend my first 4 months at Demandbase working strictly with reporting and data warehousing using fluent, S3, and Hadoop. I wrote many reports that used Ruby to call upon Pig (this is before JRuby support in Hadoop) to generate reports in the background that were then delivered to the user's email address. We used Resque (best at the time) to manage jobs, catch errors, and restart jobs when needed. This was a fantastic learning experience for me as I had never worked with a data warehouse that processed hundreds of millions of requests per day.

SR. ENGINEERING SOFTWARE DEVELOPER AT MEGAPATH; PLEASANTON, CA - MARCH 2008 - JUNE 2012Building network management and provisioning software using Ruby and Rails.
Responsibilities also include Linux systems administration, Mysql DBA, Netcool development and support.

VP SOFTWARE AND SYSTEMS ENGINEERING AT ASSETSHADOW; PLEASANTON, CA - JANUARY 2007 - MARCH 2008

I was responsible for building the entire company infrastructure from the ground up. This included the planning and implementation of all aspects of colocation facilities. I designed and implemented the network, server, and application service architectures. I lead the development team in maintaining the legacy application, written in Perl, while porting the software to Ruby and Rails. While I'm not full time any longer, I still hold this position on a contract basis.

SR. ENGINEERING SOFTWARE DEVELOPER AT MEGAPATH; PLEASANTON, CA - MAY 2001 - JANUARY 2007

Building network management and provisioning software using Perl, mysql, and eventuallyRuby and Rails. Responsibilities also include Linux systems administration, Mysql DBA, Netcool development and support. I was responsible for all systems administration for the engineering team including managing all collocations that housed servers in the network.

UNIX SYSTEMS ADMINISTRATOR, MAIL & SECURITY AT NBCI; SAN FRANCISCO, CA - JANUARY 2001 - MARCH 2001

Building network management and provisioning software using Ruby and Rails. Responsibilities also include Linux systems administration, Mysql DBA, Netcool development and support.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER AT VIP SALES COMPANY,; TULSA, OK - JANUARY 1998 - DECEMBER 2000

Informix 4GL programming, converted entire infrastructure from serial to ethernet. I also replaced all terminals with PC's and provided full support, hardware and software. I eventually wrote a lot of C++ and Powerbuilder code to convert the app to modern platforms.

Education

MODESTO JUNIOR COLLEGE; MODESTO, CA

Business, Computer Science, (MIS) 2007 - 2009 Activities and Societies: Photography

TULSA COMMUNITY COLLEGE; TULSA, OK

Computer Science, 1998 - 2000

Activities and Societies: Free Math Tutoring

UNION HIGH SCHOOL; TULSA, OKComputer Science, 1989 - 1993
Activities and Societies: DECA

Skills

Perl, MySQL, JavaScript, Unix, CSS, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Java, Android, Linux / Unix, Network Security, Network Engineering, Big Data, Hadoop, Pig, SaaS, REST, SOA Design, Sinatra, Amazon Web Services (AWS), Lean Software Development, Management, Cloud Computing, Juniper, Redback, Oracle, Linux System Administration, C#, Apache, Python, Enterprise Software, Microsoft SQL Server, Software Engineering, Agile Methodologies, Security, Bash, Web Applications, Databases, DNS, HTML, Distributed Systems, System Administration, TCP/IP, JSON, Objective-C, Git, Software Development, Web Development, Desktop Development, Mobile Development

References

Sean Crandall; VP Network Engineering; GTT: 408.781.7979

Steve Guastella; VP Engineering; TNCI: 512.784.3230

Adrienne Dale; COO; adrienne.dale@pivotal-llc.com

Ron McClain; Sr Manager Devops; DemandBase: 510.673.7621

